this
problem uses a for loop which may look a
little bit different than
other loops that we've seen in ruby
we often use for loops to iterate
through a collection
and in this code the collection is
the range of integers from 1 to 100
inclusive remember that this 2 dot
notation
is an inclusive range and three dot
notation is exclusive
now i is a variable representing each
element of the collection
as we iterate through on line two you
can see we output i
so let's run our code and look at the
output
and you can see that from 1 to 100 we've
output every element of the collection
the challenge here is to output i only
if i
is an odd number
[Music]
and we can use an if statement here to
do that
a ruby method that comes in handy for
this particular problem
is the integer method odd odd returns a
boolean
it returns true if the number is odd and
false if the number is even so let's run
our code
and if you look at our output this time
you can see that we've output
only the odd numbers
because our if statement is pretty short
we can actually move it all onto one
line
now if you didn't happen to know the
integer odd method
or know that a method existed to take
care of this logic for you
you could write out the logic yourself
we can write out our own logic here to
determine whether the
remainder of i divided by 2 is equal to
0 or not
and if not the number is odd
and again we run our code and see the
correct output
so don't be afraid to write your own
logic whether or not you know
a ruby method that can handle it for you
it's important
that you're able to write working code
without having to go method hunting and
rely
too heavily on the built-in methods
provided